To be on the consent agenda and Mike, I didn't give you heads up, but I'm going to ask that I
may be pulled out. I just want to talk about that for a second. So that would leave. If there
are no other items, four, five, six, seven, and nine staff is recommending for the consent agenda.
Do we have a motion to approve? I'll make a motion to approve the items four, five, six,
seven, seven, and nine. Okay, and a second. Oh, sorry. Roll call please.
Justin. All right. Johnson. All right. Lewis. I forced it. All right.
Shult. All right. And Mike, I apologize. I thought I could ask you this before the meeting and I did not think to tell
me a little bit about what item it is. Well, we are, we have both internet here at the city. It's currently
100 megs and due to the growth in some areas, we're going to upgrade that to one gig. Okay. So,
and that'll provide faster service for us. Okay. Yes. When you say some areas, we're actually
reaching out to do the power phone. Other agencies, first responders will now be able to see our
computer-rated dispatch system. So, they'll have real-time information, medical calls, fire calls.
So, that way when they respond, they'll have some free rival instructions. Okay. Y'all, well,
while we're speaking of both. I think we're hoping that possibly at our meeting of the 20th,
others working on that. We'd like to bring you that item that's part of our content,
plan and part of our budget, in which we may want to start working with both to see if we may
be able to bring them in for all of our customers. And, Mike, that's something we've discussed for
quite a while about trying to have gigabyte service and gigabyte community. We'll be a fairly substantial
investment on the part of my am. If we do that, but it could, in the long run, it could very well
should be worth it. And, well, the first steps will be doing some type of a survey of our community
to see if we would have the type of penetration and the type of customers that would make that work.
We wanted to get bold up and running. They had a few build-out issues that they were working on,
but all has been good. And, in fact, we were communicating with them just the last couple of days and
they've indicated that everything's still on the table and they're willing to work with us. So,
that's going to be a September project and that's part of our budget and part of our complaint.
And, Mike, as you say, to say, we wouldn't be upgrading the service if we weren't very satisfied with it.
Oh, yeah, yeah. That's, that's, that's kind of what you say.
Any other questions for Mike on this particular issue? If not, I'll make a motion to approve out of
it. I just got one there. Is this extra $300 at an budget or is that going to be?
Um, I have money in my budget that I'm moving from one account to another account to cover cost.
doing a better amendment on that. Okay.
I'll second. Okay.
We'll call please.
Chilled.
All right. Who is I?
Western?
I. Forster.
All right.
Okay.
We are going to skip item 10 for now.
Item 10 is to recognize Miami public school senior football
awards and I know they've been practicing and they are running a little bit
late. So we're going to move on to item 11.
Item 11 is Mayor's nomination for chairman and vice chairman of the Miami
Recreation Tourism Convention and Visitors Advisory Board.
And my nominees for those positions are Neil Johnson, councilman
Johnson and chairman and councilman by and forester as vice chairman.
And I don't remember if they can vote on their own nominations or not.
You're going to be best if they didn't.
So let's give it a try.
And I can't vote on my nominations.
So that would be just two.
So I think they're going to have to.
They're going to have to.
And I think we've done that before.
I just do one of the time.
Yeah. Let's do that.
Let's put them out.
And that may.
Yeah. That's a good idea.
Thank you, Neil.
So the first person that I'm nominating in is Neil Johnson as chairman.
Motion approved.
Second.
Work all please.
Western.
All right.
And then the next person I'm nominating is Brian Forster as vice chairman.
I'm like the motion approved.
Okay.
All second.
Go call please.
Okay.
Johnson.
All right.
Lewis.
Western.
All right.
Forster.
No.
Neil.
I think.
I think that's it.
Yes.
Oh no.
Thank you.
We're not confused.
We're going to move on.
We can't.
Can be simpler.
I'm.
I'm 12 is at mayor's nomination for board members to the.
For other positions on the Miami recreation tourism convention visitors.
Advisory board.
None of whom were sitting up here.
So it shouldn't be as complicated.
We're nominating here.
Crow and Ron Gilbert for four year terms.
Jennifer Hessie and Tara Elkey for three year terms.
Steve Gilbert Greg.
I'm like welcome for two year terms and Morgan Busy for one year term.
And it's my understanding that we can just vote on all those or y'all can vote on all those.
Once if you so choose.
So do we have a motion to approve.
Oh, make it.
Those people.
And the second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Western.
I.
Forster.
Lewis.
Johnson.
All right.
Thank you.
I had an 13 outside the organization contract for fiscal year 2016.
2017.
So in your packet are applications.
Financial information and the contracts.
contracts for four organizations, the Community Crisis Center, the MIMA Senior Center,
Autobocounty Graduate Stinctions, and the Grand Gate Way Pelavan.
I did in the B.A. I show you that they did it's exactly the same,
they're asking the exact same amounts that they got for 15, 16.
It is all budgeted, and we did have one organization that did not apply.
That we had last year, but did not apply for this year.
Was that the harbor?
Yeah.
And then also animal welfare?
They haven't applied for a couple years.
They were not.
Okay.
Okay. Any questions for Jill?
This is not what we met about last year.
You had a committee last year that reviewed all the applications.
So this is a new for the following 16, 17.
Yeah, for the, just go away when we're dealing with,
15, 15.
So we had a bit of a change in the process.
Yeah, I was just, when I saw that, we know over how committee, I guess,
to review it.
Is that one of that?
That's correct.
We're trying to do a stream line a bit.
We let everybody that received funding last year.
No.
That if they wanted to receive money in 16, 17 to apply,
we did put out public notice.
If there was anybody else that wanted to apply, nobody else did.
So in essence, we're just rolling it over into next fiscal year without going
through that process.
It doesn't change everything.
That's not really enough in did at all.
And the last meeting, we gave them an extended time limit to meet the requirements
that was taken care of.
That was for 15, 16 in yes.
Okay.
Yep.
They were cured, the contracts, yeah.
And these funds were also in the budget that was approved.
Correct.
Yes.
Okay.
Any other questions?
Any concerns behind you?
Have any concerns?
Okay.
Then I would entertain a motion to approve the outside organization contracts.
Please, I didn't recommend that.
One additional item before the vote, just very quickly.
You might remember when council member Lewis, and it's sorry about that.
I'm trying to be too far more here about the cure.
In this year, the wording is such that if some of the reports that we have asked for
are not submitted, then we will withhold the payment until we are able to get the reports.
We will put us in the bad situation last year.
It really wasn't all the agencies in the agencies that didn't.
It wasn't a big issue.
It was just kind of a more of a crossing tease in dotting eye situation.
So this year, we're going to be doing a lot more contract management to make sure that we do have those things in place
before we have a reimbursement, too.
Those are quarterly reports.
Yes.
Okay.
Yep.
Yeah.
So anyway, we've corrected that in this contract.
And I thought just for the record, I mentioned that, too.
Good.
We have a motion on item 13.
Much different, man.
in a second.
Awesome.
Can I roll call please?
Johnson.
Lewis.
I'm Western.
Hi.
Four stars.
I'm going to give you a second.
I'm Jordan.
Yeah.
Check for a quick.
We can always in a route to charter discussion for these two.
Two.
Six.
Four.
Brothers.
I'll give them a minute too.
One.
Two.
Three.
Every Sunday, I gave you just that's true.
I've learned to get the body here.
Same.
Good.
Two.
Four.
Twelve.
Two.
Six.
Seven.
Two.
Four.
Okay.
Well was you so fall on a problem.
I'm sorry, this is the whole thing, can I go to the other part?
Is this the whole charter that you found?
At the present time.
Yes.
So I think...
Oh, I know exactly where you got it.
I didn't know exactly where you got it.
And I believe last year when I asked which one was where you got it.
Can you hear me?
Here we go, sir.
He was going to see if the football team was out there.
I think they're just getting out of practice for much more than before we say him.
Hopefully it's hard.
I don't care if you picture with you guys.
They got helled ill.
It's Friday.
Yeah, I don't know.
Don't know much about them.
I don't know.
I understand the game that's being sponsored by Steve Homes.
Who is?
Steve is sponsoring the game Friday.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Just hold it.
Okay.
And I think we'll just give them a moment.
Good.
Yeah, I won't be throwing it just a minute.
Just a minute.
I'll get younger and younger.
We don't.
Come on.
So all the kids get younger and younger.
We don't.
Yeah.
Got on over NEO first thing they made you do they gave you a little copy of the fights
Nice we'll learn it. You didn't think if you had a big bunch of me kind of mother yourself through what the sophomores
Well then they decided to
You didn't know you got to run
Manless say I ran a lot of bleachers
Before I bring it up the fries though. I always thought those bleachers were dangerous to run. Oh they were
Yeah, they were dangerous to walk at that, but yeah, they
He definitely went to pick up your knees when you went up
The tap
No, no, no, no, I was talking about the first home game. Yeah, yeah, okay
No, they think that's where I would fix the next go
Went to Montana Mike said the night and the waiter came up he had a weakness big on a finger
I go my gosh. What is that National Championship?
He weighed about 100 and yeah, he's about 120 pounds
That's cool. He's got a heavy
I just saw something the other they put out this little brochure
You know cross one another day and it's on about the National Championship
I think they would have had either two or four
Where the National Champions and their white division and then of course they were they?
Over all National Champions
Jay set up couple
But the Pirates and Gold team currenty, but yeah, yeah
I didn't see
Okay, we are going to pick up item number 10 now, which is recognized by any public school senior football
whoardals coach I appreciate all you guys being here come on up to the podium please and tell us about your team a little bit
Tell us about these guys you got with you mr. madam councilman. Thank you for having us this evening. It's always a pleasure to come and
Visit with you and I appreciate you indulge in us and
Your schedule
Coach sheet. I'm stubborn enough not to cut practice short to get them here. So we're always grandma to make it so thank you for your time
I'm gonna start out. I let them step up here and introduce them
And then I'll talk a little bit about them. Okay, so go ahead step up and stay up there
I'll screw you on over
Trevor, so I don't know what position you play. Why do you see her?
Walk one hurry back one back. I'm just a strange. I play a water see her
My name's for show. I'm a little bit on the nose guard
Jager Paxon off that's a watch
Daniel Allen, offensive one, defense one, camera jeans, quarterback, trading break, offensive one, defense one
Isaac colored, throwing back and my back. So as you can see, and I'll mention we have 10 seniors
We have nine here, Caden Collins
I have early season injury and so he's unavailable to be here tonight, but he is our 10th senior
So these young men
I've done a great job
So far this year and they're time as being a war dog and
Really done a great job and through the transition, you know, they've been a part of
the stadium complex
Transitions some of the
modifications and upkeep that we've made just at the practice field and and and and a war dog locker room and so they've really
Have a lot to be proud of and helping and being a part of establishing
new war dog traditions as they've been through high school
9 through 12 grade so
Extremely proud of their efforts and everything that they do and some of that tradition
That this group has been a part of two sayings that we talk about a lot
One is it means something to be a word dog
If you're on social media in here, you'll see that a bunch MST B-W
Means something to be a word dog and then especially this year with this group
The few the proud the word dogs that we talk about, you know, any
Means something to run out on that field and to represent the word dogs and wear that so
We always we take pride in thanking you and everything that you get a
accomplish for us and and day-to-day
City business it affects us and we thank you for that and the stadium is one example of that and we're extremely proud and
Of that facility yes, guys
Yeah, questions for us so I win the first home game coach this Friday
We can't get off this Friday 730 versus Hilldale Hornets
They're pretty good for ball team the ranked and the top 10 coming off a good year last year
It's going to be a challenge right off the bat, but we're excited about the opportunity and again
We had a good scrimmage last Thursday after waiting out the weather and so we were excited about kicking it off
And when do we pay a greater this year grab is the last game of the year
into our district play, if you understand high school football a little bit,
uh, grow, drop down and become part of our district and so we re-drew and they
couldn't have worked out any better because you really drove from a half for
district play and we went from game one to game ten and it'll be a double
feature because it obviously be senior night since it's a last-home game so
what better senior night than against your archer rival so, and in homecoming is
uh, the 20th of second-home game which I believe is the 23rd. So you start out
home and then you're away home for a game. It's both two games. Yeah, and then
come back home for a homecoming so, do you guys have anything you're dying to share?
How practical is it today?
Well, congratulations, guys. It's all right, my best off today.
Oh, what's the tailgating start? Is it?
Well, it's tailgating is a five, five-thirty, the dog works at five-thirty. Down the alley there with the
band leading in, gates open right after the dog walk at about five, uh, fifty and tailgating keeps
going on until about six to twenty, but that's kind of the daily operations there for the
tailgating and the festivities going on. We invite you out to see that, uh, Boucher Club is a great
job. The community does a great job of getting involved with sponsoring the games and running
the tailgate and everything. So it's just a great atmosphere.
Coach, we have a co-deck moment back here. All right, let's see if there might be a round.
Yeah.
Just say they'll nail one, two, two, you know, I need you to.
There we go.
Don't crush the coach.
Coach, is it just me or is it, or are they getting bigger?
Well, they're getting a pretty good side last.
You know, and those paddles are bad, I'm sorry they're getting bigger and bigger.
What's that?
That's great.
Who got time to share it for the game?
This is perfect.
Yeah. One more. Thank you so much.
Thanks for coming.
Thanks, Coach.
Thank you.
And we'll do a round for the opportunity.
Coach, I love you.
We had it been to a world-all home game in the last couple of years.
They've really got a great tail-gating tradition started.
And I would encourage any members of the public that haven't been lately to go out and check them out.
I agree.
Well, if that were to move on, a bank tide, I'm 14, which is discussion of proposed changes for the
sort of charter.
I'd just want to make a couple of developments in advance of the discussion.
And we had the change in the form of city government and back in 2000.
And that was an important change.
I think it's a great one for our city and our community.
I think we've made a lot of progress since then.
But there were some charter issues even back then that probably should have been addressed and
didn't get addressed.
And it's time for us to cancel to take a look at those and bring ourselves further into the 20th or
century.
And so over the last couple of years when David was city attorney, we'd ask him to make some recommendations to the council.
It's a change that he felt more important.
And as Ben has come on board, we've asked him to review David's recommendations and incorporate
any that he might also have.
We're not necessarily going to try to tackle the entire charter.
But there are certainly parts of it that need to be addressed and need to be brought up to
modern standards, if you will.
With that, I'm going to turn it over to either Dean or Ben.
I'm going to.
I think Ben.
All right.
Okay.
So council members, this is a working progress.
And you have at your seats this evening, a draft that has a few minor changes from
what you would have received in your packet.
Kristen and I are still working on various things here and we anticipate that there will be more
changes as we work our way through this.
But basically what we did is we took the last draft of David's work that we were able to find and started with that.
There were a huge portions of the charter that were basically just our cake.
I really had no business being in a charter.
I suppose maybe in 1910 they had a place there, but they certainly didn't have a place today.
In addition, there were a large number of provisions in the charter that were basically just taken from and quoting state statute.
Which there's not particularly anything wrong with doing that, but the problem is that from the time to time the statutes are amended.
And then you either have to likewise amend your charter, which is not an easy thing to do.
It's certainly not as easy as amending a state statute.
Well, you have an inconsistency between your charter and the state statutes.
So, one of the things that I did, and it's in Article 1, Section 3, basically, we just
are saying that except as otherwise, specifically set out in the charter, we're adopting
the state law as it may apply, and as it may be amended so that we don't have to constantly
be making changes with the charter.
With taking those things out of the charter, it left huge gaps in what we had.
You did those things, the Arcade, the Arcade items, and the state law.
It's consistent.
Right.
Okay.
So, there were some huge gaps in the entire charter.
The charter, as it exists right now, it has nine different articles.
There are several of the articles have nothing in it.
Absolutely nothing.
And so, what I thought was probably a better way to proceed, and I'll go into a little more detail
on this in a little bit, is to consolidate it all into a more concise, and hopefully more logical document
than things being spread out all over the place.
Just as an example, under the current charter, most of the officers are described, and
their duties set out in Article II, and as the mayor of the council, the city manager of the city clerk,
but the treasure is, often, Article V, and they're just not a real logical basis for doing that.
So, what I thought would be a better way to proceed was consolidate this all into four different articles.
The first one basically setting out the powers of the city, the second one outlining who the officials of the city are,
what their duties and responsibilities are, Article III deals with the meetings, and then Article IV deals with election issues.
In the one in the version that was sitting on your desk this evening, the few just very few changes.
changes that I wanted to talk about before I get into that, though, in removing the
cake staff and removing the quotes from state statute that reduces the charter from 32
pages down to 12 pages. And it's what easier document to follow. So those items that we were
following the state documents on, how are we legally dealing with those particular issues now?
As I say in the one provision article 1, Section 3, you're incorporating the state law,
any state law that is applicable that is not contradictory what you've to what you have said
out in the charter. Okay. Okay. So the charter controls.
That's an important distinction because we're a charter community-cript. We have the right,
as a community not to deviate in some areas, in some areas. And how and then the laws that we
establish, I guess. In what you're saying is where there's not a conflict and we're just adopting the
state law. Right. Okay. Okay. Okay. So there are just a couple of changes that are reflected here
in the document that you have at your seats this evening. In what I'd previously presented,
it's in article 1, Section 1, we said that we were creating a city manager form of government.
Well, we're not really doing that with this change. We're just continuing.
That's a city manager change. The one of the questions that Christa asked and we had some discussion
about was making sure that the, it's cleared the charter that the city manager has the authority
to delegate those duties that he's given under the charter. And so we added a section. It is on page
in terms of the seventh page. And again, it gives you as the city council the right to put
restrictions on those delegations. So if you don't want something delegated, you can, you have the right
to say that that duty will not be delegated. Where we are? I mean, well, it's in Section 9.
So okay, I got you. I got you. I got you.
And I'm not exactly sure, you know, the extent of any of the conversations before I got
on board here, a great, like I mentioned earlier, a great deal of this was taken from
what David's work was, so I don't know to what extent these had been discussed earlier.
There are a couple of things, there are several minor changes, mostly wording changes that
really don't substantively change what the charter provides.
But there are a couple of places that it does have a significant difference, I think,
it's a significant difference from what the prison charter provides.
The first of those is the provision that I already mentioned that we're incorporating
the state laws, as long as it's not inconsistent with this charter.
That's a wholly new provision there on the fourth page of what you've heard from
you, and I highlighted it in yellow, at the bottom of the page, that the current charter provides
that there is no salary for serving on the city council.
I'm assuming there's been some discussion about that, but I'm not positive, but in any of that, we
have the provision here that the City Council members are entitled to share in the health
insurance that other city employees are entitled to.
That's not an unusual thing in this day and age.
I know, for instance, members of the Miami School Board are entitled to receive their health insurance
through holding that position.
It goes on to provide that a salary may be set up by ordinance that would be in addition
to the health insurance, but it goes on to specify, and this is required by the Oklahoma State
Constitution, that if there is a change in salary, it cannot be effective during the term
of anybody that is currently serving on and voting on that issue.
Now, if you get reelected and you're starting a new term, after some sort of a salary has been
voted in, then at that point you can start.
receiving it, but you cannot receive it during whatever term it is that you're sitting on when
such a salary is voted in. It doesn't say you have to. It just says that you can't.
And the only disparity there is because terms are staggered. You could have. It would be a staggered.
Could have directly started drawing a salary a year earlier than someone else. If they're work
provisions for a second. Yeah, they're all staggered. There could be as much as a two year difference.
Is that distinction also applied to the health insurance? No. Okay. So just the just if
different fact, some future council made a decision to pass on the ordinance, then that would trigger
the clock to ticking so to speak. But you, other members of that council would be eligible to
leave it through an election cycle. Okay. Now, let me back up on the health insurance. You know,
this is just a proposal. And certainly I want your feedback. We want what my goal is. And again,
I'll get into this in a little more detail here in just a minute. But my goal is to come up with something
as best we can that reflects what the five of you want and then we'll proceed from there. But if you don't
want that in there on the health insurance, we can take it out. It just to me, it made sense that
it should be in there. Now as I said earlier, but I think before the meeting started with the change in
the former government was passed in 2000, I was with a lot of other people involved in that process.
And I was one of the ones that's had strike the the paragraph that I think it was a hundred dollars
a month is what the commissioners at the time got. I thought well, they're volunteers, but you know,
having sat here now for 10 years. I see that not in sat here, but being involved in trying to recruit
people to run for city council. I think that the salary part, but I'm not so worried, but I think
something like the health insurance in particular is an important incentive that whoever future council
members are, have available to them to recruit or just be in incentive for people to want to serve.
Because everybody up here and now knows it's put a lot of time in it. And so I think it's appropriate
contrast with how I felt 15 years ago or 16 years ago about it. So in essence, being your
president and this to us and your point is, this is just a start, let's start this is a special
resource. I'm surprised it shrank that much, but a million maybe I shouldn't be surprised. I know in
David's version, you asked about the conversations about it. There were whole sections where he just said
just, you know, superseded by state statutes or we're adopting state statute, whatever the phrase
ology was.
that certainly eliminated a lot.
If someone wants to, in the future, if we take that approach and someone wants to know what
is the law on this particular issue, right now they can go to the website and reference the
charter.
Are there going to be references under specific items?
How will they find out what a, how will deal with the particular issue that's now part
of the state statute?
How are they, you know, the common light person, and what they research.
It is just as easy to go online and get the state statutes now, I will say you have
to know where to go up because there's 85 or 86 titles in the state statutes, not to
mention the state constitution, but it's not that hard to navigate.
Typically, there's four or five titles that deal with the issues that the city municipalities
immunospality would deal with, total 11 being the primary one, that's, that is, immunospalities.
Cities and towns, it's classified.
The other major change that I, I've made from the current charter is the position of the
city clerk.
I put it in here, this is on the eighth page, it's section 13, and that also is highlighted in what
you have.
The city clerk is appointed by the city manager.
That's more of a ministerial role, and so in my mind anyway, it's more appropriate for
it to come under the administration aspect that the city manager provides.
The city treasurer is still in this version appointed by youth at the council.
The other major thing that I would want to point out is not a change, but how it stays the same.
The election cycle, the cycle of terms for the council positions remains the same as they are right now.
So if you, let's say this was voted in by the voters next year, and the mayor is the one that is up for election next year,
you would still be up for election next year.
And then whoever, the two, the rep for election, the following year are still up for election, the following year,
and then the remaining two, the year after that.
I'm just on that this out here.
I'm not saying I'm foreign, it just may be a thought we may fight about.
I know there's some communities do four-year term.
I don't know whether that's something we might want to look at.
I don't know.
When we made the change, we went from two-year terms to three-year-stagger terms.
So we have increased it 15 years ago, and the logic for this dagger terms was simply to provide
a mechanism for institutional memory.
When they had the change in the former government, I think four of the five council members,
the mayor and three council members left, if you will, the next election cycle, I think
Danny was the only one that remained active.
So that's the purpose of the staggering, is just to provide that institutional memory.
As far as the terms go, we did increase it from two to three, and it's my last term.
So for example, there's nothing magical about it, it works out well mathematically.
The four-year work, the three, with five member board counting the mayor, the mayor being the one by
himself, and then the two on each of the other years.
If you go to a four-year term, that compensates a little mathematically, nothing unsurmountable.
So that's the just of my proposal, at this point in time, what I would suggest is that we continue
to work on this, to get the draft, as I said, in a firm that is acceptable to you, to the
five of you, as best we can, then start a public forum dialogue, expose it to the citizens, let them
come in and ask questions and make suggestions, and go through that process.
If there are other changes to be made after that, we can get those made, and then go to a vote of the people.
What the format for the vote that I would be recommending is under Title 11, Section 13,
Section 1112, it allows for, and I think that this is important, it allows to
repeal your present charter, and at the same time, in the same vote, put in place your new charter.
Because without doing that, it really gets complicated because, like I said, the current
who has nine articles, the provisions that would be remaining or spread all over the place.
So rather than trying to reach the juxtaposition of this one versus that one, just repeat
it, then put it in place with the new provision with whatever it is that we have at that
point.
It is much easier to navigate on 12 pages.
Yes.
32.
I was a little overwhelming.
So the bill, can you walk us through the calendar that you are recommending?
Well, the election specifically.
You also have it, you see, I believe, a commenter that shows what the election cycle is and
quite frankly, at least you have got this and I have been studied at that.
We would fit it in to work on this cycle, the regular election right now for the
to fill your vacancy, which we will come about, is, before it's the highlighted one.
Yes, there it is.
They prefer the election.
And at that same election, you can do propositions.
So the resolution would be due January 20 if I'm reading this correctly, and there's of course
the filing period for the election, but for the purposes of this particular item, January 20
is when this resolution is due to the election board.
Correct.
And so from January 20 back, if we wanted to have some educational meetings, open meetings,
forms, we're at the end of August now, so we would have to start that.
So we have to give you time, but not that much time.
So I would say certainly in November, at the latest, you'd want to be having those.
Maybe I brought it after the general election because it's right before people are going to
be perhaps distracted.
And then leave us a lot of time to do changes though, I'd like to think about that a little bit.
Back up just a little bit to one of your sort of questions earlier was, you know, comments,
you weren't sure how much conversation had taken place before you came on the scene.
And there's been a conversation over the years, I think, some of it, you know, as individuals
would David those of us that have been here for a while.
And in some of it, you know, in these forms, but it's
It's really just always been around how do we get rid of the archaic stuff and how do we do what you described earlier
rather than repeating what was at one time the state law that may have been changed and repealed,
how do we simplify that and it sounds like that you've come up with mechanisms for dealing with both of those
and it's just up to us to read through this now.
I know that they did provide copies of the link to your document
and I would ask that you do take the time to go through there and read through this if there's
something that you think is, quote, missing, that's important and we need to come back and
we, you know, the next meeting and talk about that and you know, why we think it's important but
I'm pretty comfortable that Ben has captured at least 90 percent of what we're trying to accomplish
just with the two steps he's taken already and that's all I've got to say and I don't know
what we want to read through this tonight I would ask you to take it with you and read it.
I would like to go ahead and put this on the next regular council agenda and know we've talked about doing this
in work sessions but given that we don't have about a couple more of these until the November time
I would like to at least have it as an agenda item for discussion if there's things that the
particular council portion wants to bring up and that would be the insurance I'd like to see what that
looks like if we could put some numbers together and see what possibly we'd be looking at first.
Oh we could easily do that. One thing I just wanted to point out our next meeting is going to be on September
20th and then we would have the meeting up at least scheduled on September 27th which will be our study session
so we could you know at the end of September we could have two meetings one after the other
and two weeks. So so let's everybody try to get through this before that first meeting in the
girl event on the meeting on the 20th is just to come back and say to staff here are the questions
are being here's things we need you to think about probably next week's meeting.
Yeah I think I couldn't get that there easily. I'm assuming that everybody has gotten a copy of
what I got which is David's pretty extensive notes which really outlines a lot of the history of
everything that we have in our charter at the present time. I thought that was very good but I didn't
think it was necessary for purposes of what we were doing here. And I'd also just comment that David
sent a text message late this afternoon with some other proposals which I have not had the chance to
look at. So there may be some other things that he came up with after soon after he should be viewed
as a child we're going to be a lot. I just hadn't read it but there's a chart for a change.
to do was give us kind of some historical context,
which I think is helpful to know why it looks the way it looks.
But what we're going to end up though
with is something nice and clean like this.
I think it even David's version ultimately
would have got us in the same spot just without the history.
OK?
Any other questions for a being on this issue?
OK, thank you, Ben.
We are then going to move out of 15, which is staff reports,
so we're going to put it in your packet and stand.
Was it available if you have questions?
I've got one, if no boils.
There's anything, right?
You know, I bet on our sugar.
I believe toward the end of this month, which is a couple of days.
And it sounds like we're probably getting down to a punch list.
Oh, I was at the end of the show.
And I don't know, shall we?
OK.
So I think we're getting down to a punch list.
And we're actually talking about starting to work on some kind of a
dedication, the signage, and things such as that.
So we're right there, but I believe sometime after Labor Day
will start going on with it.
Anything else?
OK, a city manager to be in case is deep.
I have two items.
I want to just remind everybody.
We have already posted this on our Facebook page,
and we've reposted it.
But as part of the road projects that we're working on with
also in associates, we had kind of a survey and suggestions from
citizens, and we've had a lot of them already.
And we've just reposted it, and also to remind you that we're actually
going to have a live meeting on September 1st in the banquet room here at
the Civic Center from 5 to 8 p.m.
If you ever been to one of these, basically, it's very similar to what we
did when we did our comprehensive plan.
We'll have different maps and signage sheets set up and by
citizens to come and basically, if they just want to say, you know,
the street in front of my house needs attention, or they have concerns about
their utilities, they have the ability to come in and do that.
The public participation that we wanted to have as part of this project,
or a reminder that we want to have a kind of finished product,
taking care of my October 31st.
That's what's in our contract with Olson.
And long before then, we want to start bringing you some of the results.
So that'll probably be something we'll be doing in late September early October as well.
So it's an opportunity for our citizens, and as I said,
we're getting a lot of good feedback as it is right now.
So if you're available on, we'll be putting out a notice of attendance for you
if you want to come for that as well.
That's Thursday.
That's Thursday from 5 to 8.
It's coming out.
So there's no program with people show up at 7.55 and they want to give us some feedback.
That's fine.
Now, you mentioned originally, we start talking about the road program.
And then you also mention utilities utilities will follow a month after that, and this also
Yes, because we have to we have that finished product at the end of November
But what we've done is we've combined both so we're having comments that are about roads
We have comments about utility problems as well and issues for attention
Also an associate's representatives will be here. Yes, for the rather part and then there's no utilities
Yes, but for this meeting is for both roads
And utilities but what also in his doing is they will have one
Program for roads which is due on October 31st and then a secondary program on utilities
Which is due on no bet at the end of November when you're saying program you mean a
Recommendations what projects to start working on how we kind of combine both
Projects that we go out to bid for and projects that we do in house
So on this September 1st meeting they're going to have their recommendation. No, that what this is
This is a public meeting. This is to get information from our system. They're providing no information to this is a lot
They've been it's an opportunity for our citizens can to come in and talk to us and again
It's roads and utility roads and utilities are to absolutely
Okay, the second item is on Friday, or excuse me Saturday, September 3rd at
130 the class of 1966 will be doing the unveiling of the seat owns both more
So I'm kind of happy to see that come to
Class of 1966, yes, and if you want to attend again we'll do a notice of the attendance for you
If you'd like to be there and we have a tariff over it, so we'll be able to kind of do the actual unveiling
We're not I think we'll have members of the Steve Owens family there and we'll also have members of the Ted Watts family there as well
And J.D. Stauder we got I think is leading all this because she's part of the class of 1966 as well
And our coosaut of real estate bank is kind of enough to let us park in his parking lot at the new well state banks
There should be ample parking if you want to be there as well. I have a text message today said somebody said I think somebody from all
Where she's scheduled this and the problem with that is what
He's still a way
That's case one was out of my apartment
Maybe we'll be 15 and a half time. We'll have to worry about it depends on who's at that 50 and nothing
That's true okay
That's true to
Okay, and that's it for me
That's it
Any other comments if not I am 17 is
I'll see you in a second.
Okay roll call please.
Western.
Aye.
I.
Forster.
Aye.
Show.
Thank you everyone.
Please register.